If you want to know how to make
delicious soft serve ice cream in the
Goumia softs serve ice cream machine,
then stay tuned and I'll show you how to
make this delicious ice cream that
actually keeps [music]
its shape.
Yep. I was going to do this video last
week, but did [music] the chocolate
comfort ice cream instead. Here it is.
Dusted this off. I don't use this very
much because I'm more of a hard ice
cream kind of guy, but loads of people
have asked me for more more recipes for
soft serve. So, that's what we're going
to do today. So, let's pop this on the
floor and very briefly talk about why
soft serve recipes are different to
normal American hard or gelato ice
creams. Soft serve recipes generally
have uh a very average amount of fat,
somewhere between 10 and 12% fat
content. But more importantly, it's the
sugar content. Soft serve sugar content
is nominal because it needs to freeze in
a slightly different way to normal US
hard ice cream. In soft serve machines,
they are churned in a horizontal batch
freezer and that is where this gourmet
machine actually really does perform
better than most other ones because in a
standard ice cream machine, you've got
your bowl there and it churns this way.
It is very difficult to include air in a
machine that does it like that. But
horizontal machines, churning machines
actually do a much better job at
incorporating air. So that's a real
bonus for this gourmet machine.
That's the basics of soft serve. I'll go
into more detail on Patreon and for
YouTube supporters. But for now, let's
look at what we're going to need for
this chocolate soft serve ice cream. So,
you are going to need 480 gram of whole
milk, 200 g of cream from 33 to 36%
fat, 40 g of skim milk powder, 140 g of
sugar, 50 g of unsweetened cocoa powder,
little pinch of salt, 1 teaspoon of
vanilla extract, and I do recommend you
use something like guar at 0.2 or 0.3
g. Now, the guard is to help stabilize
because soft serve needs to be a very
specific texture. So, let's just get on
and make this. First thing we're going
to do is get everything weighed out
ready. Right. So, let's get started with
our milk. 480
g.
Into that goes 200 g of our cream. Into
a small container, we're going to weigh
our dry ingredients. So, is our sugar
140 g.
Skin milk powder 40 g. A little pinch of
salt. cocoa powder. Use a strong profile
cocoa powder if you can. I'm going to
use the fries that I used in last week's
video. It's actually pretty decent. We
need 50 grams of our cocoa powder. And
finally, our gu, which is 2 to.3 g. Not
a huge amount. Let's tidy some of this
up. So, we got two other things left.
Super important things. We got our
vanilla extract, which we're not going
to put in until we've heated it and it's
cooled down a little bit. And my coffee.
Our dry ingredients. We're now just
going to whisk those together. Again,
whisking to break up any large clumps to
distribute that gua within our mix as
well. With that combined, that can go
into our liquid. And we're going to stir
this together and get it on heat. We got
goo in this recipe, but that's a cold
process stabilizer. We don't need to
heat this up super high. We're just
going to heat this up enough to
dissipate and dissolve that cocoa
powder. So, somewhere around a 50 55
Celsius mark. So, let's get it up to
there and then bring it back. Right,
with our soft serve ice cream base off
the heat, I've let it cool down for a
few minutes now and we can put our
vanilla extract in. Put it in when it's
too hot. So, you know, 60° you'll burn
off a lot of that volatile alcohol that
goes into making this and change the
recipe structure. So, let it cool down
one teaspoon. If you're unsure, you
absolutely can put this in after it's
completely chilled down because we're
about to put this in the fridge
overnight. So, with that in mind,
let's get this chilled down. If you want
to use an ice bath to cool this down, by
all means, we do need to allow this to
rest. So, I'm going to leave this in the
refrigerator overnight so that the
stabilizer has got time to completely
hydrate and our serum phase, which is
not something I've really discussed
before, has time to bond with the rest
of the ingredients. So, in we go.
That is going to go in the fridge
overnight, and we'll come back tomorrow
when we churn it. Right, let's
get this mixed back up.
We're on. Let's pour this inside.
Right, soft serve. Let's go.
while we unload the machine. There we
go. Image on the screen. Our chocolate
soft serve with salted caramel sauce
over the top.
Really nice soft serve texture.
Let's just shut that up. Really nice
soft serve texture. Different to hard
ice cream. Like I said earlier, it the
balance is different, the freezing point
is different, and the serving
temperature is different. So, you can
put hard ice cream in here, but it will
not act the same as soft serve. So, keep
that in mind. But we've got
here we go, the first one. And then
obviously the second one with a caramel
sauce on holding its shape, not turning
into liquid straight away. Good kind of,
you know, hold just like you'd expect
from the stores. This is the kind of
consistency that you need if you want to
dip this into chocolate and then it go
hard. That's a very viral thing over the
last couple of years. You need to get
that recipe right if that's something
you want to do. If you want to do it,
then make homemade magic shell ice cream
topping, which is essentially just
chocolate and a neutral oil like coconut
oil, unflavored coconut oil, so refined
coconut oil. I actually quite like olive
oil with chocolate. Um, and the oil
changes the consistency of the
chocolate, means you can dip it and then
it just goes hard. So, there we go.
There's that. That's kind of staying
there. [music] And yeah, chocolate soft
serve.
There we go. Chocolate soft serve. Super
easy recipe to make. Different to US
hard ice cream and gelato. If you want
to see some more soft serve recipes, let
me know in the comments. Don't forget to
like and subscribe and I will see you
next week when I make something else.